Guide to the Mary C. Schlosser Collection of Harriet Beecher Stowe, 1838-2021 (bulk 1852-1934)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Mary C. Schlosser Collection of Harriet Beecher Stowe
1838-2021
1852-1934
Schlosser, Mary C.
8.2 cubic feet (15 boxes), 4 map case folders, 2 framed items
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The collection consists of published articles, printed ephemera, visual media, and a variety of popular culture artifacts and realia related to American author and abolitionist Harriet Beecher Stowe and her most popular novel, Uncle Tom's Cabin.
Biographical Note
Harriet Beecher Stowe (1811-1896) was an American author and abolitionist best known for her divisive and best-selling novel, Uncle Tom's Cabin. She was born on June 14, 1811, in Litchfield, Connecticut, to Roxana Foote Beecher and prominent Calvinist Congregational minister and abolitionist Lyman Beecher. The sixth of eleven children, Stowe's siblings included educator and author Catherine Beecher and preacher and fellow abolitionist Henry Ward Beecher. She received a classical education at Litchfield Female Academy and Hartford Female Seminary, a school run by her older sister Catherine. Stowe taught at Hartford Female Seminary from 1829 to 1832, before relocating with her father to Cincinnati, Ohio, where he had accepted the position of president at Lane Theological Seminary. While at Lane Seminary, Stowe would publish her first book, Primary Geography (1833), and marry Calvin Stowe, a professor at the Seminary. In 1851, the Stowes would move to Brunswick Maine, where Calvin had accepted a teaching position at Bowdoin College.
In 1850, the passage of the Fugitive Slave Act forced states in which slavery was illegal to cooperate in the capture and return of escaped African-Americans back to slavery. This law forced many Northerners, who until that point held passive anti-slavery positions, to become either actively complicit in the enslavement of their neighbors, or active dissidents. Turmoil was especially strong in Cincinnati, a city that existed on the border of the free state of Ohio and the slave state of Kentucky. In part inspired by the Fugitive Slave Act and by increasing unrest in the North, Stowe wrote Uncle Tom's Cabin; or, Life Among the Lowly, a work which condemned the institution of slavery and all of its participants. The book was released in March 1852 and sold 300,000 copies in its first year. By the end of the nineteenth century, it was outsold only by the Bible.
The impact of Uncle Tom's Cabin was widespread and divisive, sparking outrage from the South and becoming the first book to be banned by the Confederate government after the start of the Civil War. Stowe used her and the novel's popularity to tour nationally and internationally to speak about the book and the abolitionist cause. In the decades following the book's publication, more limited copyright laws at the time allowed the novel to be adapted in a variety of ways; from travelling theatrical performances, to translations and abridged editions, to its first motion picture adaptation in 1903.
The first major adaptation of the novel for the stage was produced by the George Howard Company using a script adapted by George Aiken which remained faithful to the novel's abolitionist messaging. Later adaptations, particularly those that toured in Southern states, would be dramatized further and altered to suit the narrative preferences of the audience. In Southern states, the harsh reality of life for enslaved people in the novel would be softened, alternate endings where Tom is happy to remain enslaved were introduced, and the African American characters of the cast would be reduced to grotesque racial caricatures, often portrayed by white actors in blackface. These touring "Tom shows" dominated the U.S. tour market by the 1880s, often featuring parades, bands, and sideshows to draw larger crowds.
In 1863, Stowe and her family relocated to Hartford, Connecticut, where she would live until her death in 1896.
References
Ford, Jane, "The Story of 'Uncle Tom's Cabin' Spread from Novel to Theater and Screen," UVA Today, University of Virginia, 12 November 2012. https://news.virginia.edu/content/story-uncle-tom-s-cabin-spread-novel-theater-and-screen
Patkus, Ronald D. and Mary C. Schlosser, "Aspects of the Publishing History of Uncle Tom's Cabin, 1851-1900," Uncle Tom's Cabin in Print: The Collection of Mary C. Schlosser, Poughkeepsie, N.Y.: Vassar College, 2004. https://www.vassar.edu/specialcollections/exhibit-highlights/2001-2005/stowe/essay2.html
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of printed ephemera, visual media, sheet music, and a variety of popular culture artifacts and realia related to American author and abolitionist Harriet Beecher Stowe and her most popular and divisive novel, Uncle Tom's Cabin, collected by Mary C. Schlosser. A small collection of letters written by members of the Beecher family, including Catherine Beecher, Isabella Beecher Hooker, and Lyman Beecher Stowe, is also included. The collection contains a variety of material related to stage adaptations of Uncle Tom's Cabin, including advertisements, playbills, programs, posters and illustrated sheet music, as well as actor cards and other memorabilia. Visual media in the collection consists of lantern slides of scenes from the novel, lithograph prints, original paintings, and posters depicting scenes from the novel as well as stage adaptations. The realia portion of the collection contains a wide variety of material culture objects, from card games and toys, to cereal boxes, to pottery and sculpture of scenes and characters from Uncle Tom's Cabin. A small amount of material related to Stowe's second anti-slavery novel Dred: A Tale of the Great Dismal Swamp (1856), is also included.
Content Warning
This collection contains a multitude of works derived from Harriet Beecher Stowe's Uncle Tom's Cabin that were created predominantly in the United States and Great Britain in the years between the American Civil War and the Civil Rights Movement of the 1960s. As such, many materials in this collection contain images and language that are racist, xenophobic, or otherwise harmful. The Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library does not support or condone these depictions, but we believe that they provide important evidence of historical realities that should not be forgotten or ignored.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series: Series I. Printed Ephemera, Series II. Sheet Music, Series III. Visual Media, Series IV. Realia, Series V. Audiovisual Media, Series VI. Beecher Family Papers, and Series VII. Catalogued Materials.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Autograph Files, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Henry Ward Beecher Collection, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Lyman Beecher Collection, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Susan B. Anthony Papers, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Separated Materials
Rare books and pamphlets, as well as a number of periodicals and broadsides, were separated from the collection and catalogued as part of the Archives and Special Collections Library Rare Book Collection. These items can be found by searching the Vassar College Libraries online catalog for the Mary C. Schlosser Collection of Harriet Beecher Stowe, as well as listed at the end of this guide as Series VI. Catalogued Materials.
Subject Headings
Names:
Aiken, George L., 1830-1876; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887; Corbaux, Louisa, 1808-1889?; Duncan Sisters; Jefferys, Charles, 1807-1865; Linley, George, 1798-1865; Little Eva (Fictitious character from Stowe); Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896; Uncle Tom (fictitious character)
Subjects:
Abolitionists; African Americans in art--19th century; African Americans in literature--19th century; African Americans in popular culture--United States; Antislavery movements--United States--19th century; Blackface; Blackface minstrel shows--United States; Literature--Adaptations; Popular culture and literature--United States; Slavery--Anti-slavery movements; Slavery--United States; Stage adaptations; Women--Suffrage; Women abolitionists--United States; Women social reformers; Women's rights
Document Types:
Advertisements; Broadsides (notices); Clippings (information artifacts); Ceramics (object genre); Fliers (printed matter); Lantern slides; Lithographs; Newspapers; Optical discs; Paintings (visual works); Pamphlets; Phonograph records; Playbills; Postcards; Posters; Prints (visual works); Programs (documents); Realia; Scores (documents for music); Sculpture (visual works); Sheet music; Sound recordings; Toys (recreational artifacts); Trade cards
VCL Categories:
African Americans; Literature and Writing; Music; Politics; Slavery and Antislavery; Theater, Drama, and Film; Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, May 2024. Updated, February 2025.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary C. Schlosser, 2019-2023. [M2019-043, M2023-003]
Series List
- Series I. Printed Ephemera, 1840-2017; [Boxes 1-2, 10, 13-14]
  This series consists of printed materials related to Harriet Beecher Stowe, Uncle Tom's Cabin, and various theatrical adaptations of Uncle Tom's Cabin. Includes advertisements, broadsides, clippings, leaflets, pamphlets, biography cards, photograph cards, postcards, event programs, some newspapers, and trade cards for various products.
  Arranged alphabetically by material type and sub-arranged alphabetically by author or title.
- Series II. Sheet Music, circa 1852 - circa 1925; [Boxes 1, 11]
  This series consists of published sheet music for various theatrical adaptations of Uncle Tom's Cabin and derivative works, such as the Duncan Sisters' Topsy and Eva, as well as Stowe's second novel Dred. Cover illustrations of sheet music are included in addition to full sheet music publications.
  Arranged alphabetically by lyricist or title, with sheet music covers filed at the end of the sequence.
- Series III. Visual Media, 1852 - circa 1927; [Boxes 1, 3, 7-9, 12-14]
  This series consists of lantern slides, lithographs, paintings, photographs, and posters of scenes from Uncle Tom's Cabin, as well as of theatrical adaptations of the novel.
  Arranged alphabetically by material type and sub-arranged alphabetically by artist or title.
- Series IV. Realia, 1852-2021, undated; [Boxes 1-7, 12]
  This series consists of assorted physical culture materials related to Harriet Beecher Stowe and Uncle Tom's Cabin, including jewelry, card games, ceramic sculptures and figurines, plates, pitchers, tins, handkerchiefs, bags, napkins, clothing, toys, wallpaper panels, and other assorted items.
  Arranged alphabetically by material type and sub-arranged alphabetically by title.
- Series V. Audiovisual Media, [1968?]-2014; [Boxes 2, 15]
  This series consists of video and audio recordings related to Uncle Tom's Cabin and derivative works, including a compact disc, a DVD, and two phonograph records.
- Series VI. Beecher Family Papers, 1836-1947; [Box 2]
  This series contains correspondence related to members of the Beecher family, including Harriet Beecher Stowe's sisters, Catherine Beecher and Isabella Beecher Hooker, and, her son, Lyman Beecher Stowe.
  Arranged alphabetically by name.
- Series VII. Catalogued Materials, 1838-2017; [102 items]
  This series consists of printed materials that were separated from the collection for cataloging. Materials include issues of newspapers, periodicals, magazines, and other printed media containing articles and short stories written by Harriet Beecher Stowe or written by others about Stowe and her works, primarily Uncle Tom's Cabin, or other members of the Beecher family.
Container List
- Series I. Printed Ephemera, 1840-2017
  - Advertisements
    - "Announcement of the 1882 youth's companion, fifty-fifth volume," Boston: Perry Mason & Co., 1881 (Folder 1.1)
    - "Carl Laemmle presents Uncle Tom's Cabin by Harriet Beecher Stowe - A Harry Pollard production,", circa 1927 (Folder 10.1)
    - "Dred by Harriet Beecher Stowe," Boston: Phillips, Ampson & Company, 1856 (Folder 1.2)
    - "Jefferys' Edition of Songs from Uncle Tom's Cabin,", 1952 (Folder 10.1)
    - "Lord Tom the Musical," York Theater Company, Theater at Saint Peter's, New York, 2015 (Folder 1.3)
    - "Uncle Tom Learns to Write," London: Lloyd's, 1852 (Folder 14.1 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin..." J. Walter Thompson Company, undated (Folder 10.1)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, a COLORAMA Features Release with a cast of thousands. Told by Raymond Massey,", circa 1927 (Folder 10.1)
  - Articles
    - Doctor Judd, "How Uncle Tom's Cabin Came to Be Dramatized," The Billboard, 2009; [printout] (Folder 1.4)
  - Biography cards
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, Grolier Inc., 1994 (Folder 1.5)
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, USA: Panarizon Publishing Corp., 1979 (Folder 1.6)
  - Broadsides
    - "Golden Rod Showboat Montrose Hotel Landing Presenting Uncle Tom's Cabin,", undated (Folder 14.1 (Oversize))
    - "Parsons & Pool's Famous Ideal Uncle Tom's Cabin Co. and Tennessee Jubilee Singers," Providence, RI: W. Hatcheer Print, [1890s?]; [61 x 25 cm, brown] (Folder 14.2 (Oversize))
    - "Parsons & Pool's Original Uncle Tom's Cabin," Providence, RI: W. Hatcheer Print, [1890s?]; [61 x 25 cm, orange] (Folder 14.2 (Oversize))
    - "Parsons & Pool's Original Uncle Tom's Cabin," Providence, RI: W. Hatcheer Print, [1890s?]; [61 x 25 cm, orange, faded] (Folder 14.3 (Oversize))
    - "Parsons & Pool's Original Uncle Tom's Cabin," Providence, RI: W. Hatcheer Print, [1890s?]; [61 x 25 cm, purple] [2 copies] (Folder 14.3 (Oversize))
    - "Slave Life! Or, Uncle Tom's Cabin," Theatre Royal, Adelphi, Nassau Steam Press, 1852; [51 x 51 cm] (Folder 14.4 (Oversize))
    - "Stetson's Big Uncle Tom's Cabin," Curtiss Show Print, Continental, Ohio, undated; [framed, 73 x 29 cm] (Framed Storage 1.6)
    - "Terry's Metropolitan Uncle Tom's Cabin Co.," Coalgate [Oklahoma] Theatre, circa 1890s; [71 x 53 cm] (Folder 14.4 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Neal Stock Company, [1882?] (Folder 13.1 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," New Theatre Royal, Bristol, 1879 Feb; [framed, 77 x 25 cm] (Framed Storage 1.6)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin!! Embracing the entire Work of Mrs. Harriet Beecher Stowe at the National Theatre," New York: Cameron's Power Presses, 1853 (Folder 13.1 (Oversize))
    - "Wm. Kibble Presents Al. W. Martin's Uncle Tom's Cabin Co.,", undated (Folder 14.4 (Oversize))
  - Brochure
    - "World Famous Uncle Tom's Cabin Museum," Dresden, Ontario, Canada, undated (Folder 1.7)
  - Calendars
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe Center, Joseph Merritt & Company, 2008 (Folder 13.2 (Oversize))
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, Springfield, MA: Massachusetts Mutual Life Co., 1893; [cover only] (Folder 1.8)
  - Call Notice
    - Stetson's Uncle Tom's Cabin Company, 1900 (Folder 2.1)
  - Clippings
    - Advertisement for Uncle Tom's Cabin at the Bowery Theatre, The New York Herald, 1854 Jan 19 (Folder 10.2)
    - "La Cabine de L'Oncle Tom," reproduced from The Old Print Shop, Inc., undated (Folder 10.2)
    - Daumier, Honore cartoon in Le Charivari, Actualities No. 52, Paris, 1852 (Folder 10.2)
    - Gillam, "The Last Scene In Uncle Grover's Cabin - The Death of Little Eva Democracy," Judge, 1889 Feb 16 (Folder 10.3)
    - "Harriet B. Stowe Dead," Hartford: The Sun, 1896 Jul 2 (Folder 14.5 (Oversize))
    - Illustration from unknown edition of Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated (Folder 1.9)
    - Nilsen, Anders, "Sketchbook / Graphic Review," New York Times Book Review, 2017 Jun 25 (Folder 10.3)
    - Photograph of Harriet Beecher Stowe from 1876, undated (Folder 1.10)
    - "The Political Topsy,", 1852 Oct 23 (Folder 1.11)
    - "Scene from the New Drama of Uncle Tom's Cabin at the Olympic Theatre," The Illustrated London News, 1852 Oct 2 (Folder 10.3)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," painted by Edward V. Brewer, Needlecraft, 1921 May (Folder 10.3)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin featuring Margeurite Clark," by Imperial the House of Personality, The Bulletin: San Francisco, 1918 Aug 24 (Folder 14.5 (Oversize))
  - Dust jacket
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, Uncle Tom's Cabin, New York: Barse & Hopkins, undated (Folder 1.12)
  - Envelope
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, 1984 (Folder 1.13)
  - Film advertisement
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Theatre News, circa 1927 (Folder 1.14)
  - Film brochure
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Universal Pictures, undated (Folder 1.15)
  - Invitation
    - "Ladies Day at the Grolier Club,", undated (Folder 1.16)
  - Leaflets
    - "An Appeal to the Women of the United States by the National Woman Suffrage and Educational Committee, Washington, D.C.," Hartford, CT: Case, Lockwood & Brainard, Printers, 1871 (Folder 2.34)
    - Blackwell, Alice Stone, "Easter Greetings", undated (Folder 1.17)
    - Colonial Theatre, Albany, NY, undated (Folder 1.18)
    - "Coming! The Standard Combination in the Great Moral Drama, Uncle Tom's Cabin", undated (Folder 1.19)
    - Hooker, Isabella Beecher, "Declaration and Pledge of the Women of the United States, Informally Proposed and Adopted by the Women's Suffrage Convention at Washington, D.C., Jan. 12, 1871," New York: Journeymen Printers' Co-Operative Association (Folder 2.35)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin" (Made in Germany), undated (Folder 1.20)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Boston Museum, advertisement, 1876 (Folder 2.2)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin Historic Site Tour Guide", undated (Folder 1.21)
  - Newspapers
    - The Independent, 1856 Apr 24 (Folder 13.3 (Oversize))
  - Photograph Cards
    - The Duncan Sisters as Topsy and Eva, signed, 1927 (Folder 1.22)
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, undated (Folder 1.23)
    - "Stetson's Uncle Tom's Cabin Company," actor profiles, Cincinnati: Hennegan & Co., undated (Folder 1.24)
    - "Uncle Tom and Little Eva," New York: Underwood & Underwood Publishers, circa 1895 (Folder 1.25)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, "Blanche Slader as Topsy" and "Little Pansy as Eva,", circa 1860 (Folder 1.26)
  - Playbills
    - Harriet, Henry Miller's Theater, 1943 Jun 13 (Folder 1.27)
    - "Sterling Bros. Big Uncle Tom's Cabin,", circa 1920s (Folder 1.28)
    - "Stetson's Big Double Uncle Tom's Cabin," Marquette Opera House, 1910 (Folder 1.29)
    - "Galley Slave," with advertisement for Uncle Tom's Cabin, [1879?] (Folder 2.3)
    - "Parsons & Pool's Famous Ideal Uncle Tom's Cabin," Keene, [NH?], circa 1870s (Folder 10.4)
    - "Terry's Big Uncle Tom's Cabin Tent Show," St. Paul, MN: Standard, [1934?] (Folder 10.4)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Parsons & Pool's Famous Ideal Theater Company, undated (Folder 2.4)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Pittsfield Opera House, Pittsfield, NH: Analecta Print, 1892 (Folder 10.5)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Royal Lyceum, Toronto: Leader Steam Press Printing, 1869 (Folder 10.5)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, A Tale of Life Among the Lowly!," Royal Lyceum, Daily Telegraph Print, undated (Folder 10.5)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, or, Life Among the Lowly," Boston Museum, 1852 (Folder 14.5 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin in Five Acts," Geo. E. Engesser's Big Railroad Shows, circa 1920 (Folder 2.5)
  - Postcards
    - "Brunswick, Maine, the house in which Uncle Tom's Cabin was written,", undated (Folder 1.30)
    - Churchill reading Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated (Folder 1.31)
    - "Grand Production of Uncle Tom's Cabin," Gettysburg: Harmount's Big Uncle Tom's Cabin Co., circa 1910 (Folder 1.32)
    - "Secret Dweller" by Harriet Beecher Stowe and "Fellowship" by D. Willia Caffray, undated (Folder 1.33)
    - "The Trio Uncle Tom's Cabin Co.,", 1910s (Folder 1.34)
    - "Uncle Tom, an old-fashioned Southern negro,", undated (Folder 1.35)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, Valentine & Sons Ltd., circa 1880 (Folder 1.36)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin 100th Anniversary Exhibition at the Chicago Historical Society,", circa 1952 (Folder 1.37)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabins at Stamford Center, Niagara Falls,", undated (Folder 1.38)
  - Programs
    - "Anthony & Ellis' Famous Ideal Uncle Tom's Cabin Company,", undated (Folder 1.39)
    - "Anthony & Parsons' Uncle Tom's Cabin Company,", undated (Folder 1.40)
    - "The Duncan Sisters in Topsy and Eva," Sam H. Harris Theatre, 1925 (Folder 1.41)
    - "F. C. Perry's Big Uncle Tom's Cabin and Speciality Company," New York: Will Rossiter, circa 1896 (Folder 1.42)
    - "The Great Moral Drama of Uncle Tom's Cabin, or, Life Among the Lowly," Daily Programme, Rochester, NY, 1866 Jan 5 (Folder 10.6)
    - "Helen Hayes in Harriet, circa 1943 (Folder 2.6)
    - "Lord Tom: A New American Musical," The York Theater Company, 2015 (Folder 1.43)
    - Neale, Frederick, "Uncle Tom's Cabin, or, Harlequin and Lucy Neal," Green's Juvenile Drama, 1853 (Folder 1.44)
    - "Onkel Tom's Hütte," Ring Theater, Vienna, 1879 (Folder 1.45)
    - Pike Opera House, Cincinnati, Season 93-94, circa 1910s (Folder 1.46)
    - "The Players Twelfth Annual Revival Uncle Tom's Cabin," Alvin Theatre, NY, 1933 (Folder 10.6)
    - "Sterling Bros. World's Largest Uncle Tom's Cabin,", undated (Folder 13.4 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin,", undated (Folder 1.47)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Academy of Music, Philadelphia, 1886 Feb 6 (Folder 10.6)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Boston Theatre, Boston: F.A. Searle Printer, 1868 (Folder 13.4 (Oversize))
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Colonial Theatre, [Boston?], undated (Folder 1.48)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Ed. F. Davis, undated (Folder 2.7)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Union City, circa 1892 (Folder 1.49)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," The Wilbur Comic Opera Company, undated (Folder 1.50)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin: a great wrong righted," Abbey's Double Mammoth Uncle Tom's Cabin Co., 1886-1887; [3 copies] (Folder 1.51)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, A Tale of Life Among the Lowly," W. E. Dewey's Pavillion, undated (Folder 1.52)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, Philadelphia Academy of Music Revival," Philadelphia: Allen, Lane & Scott, 1877 (Folder 10.7)
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin with Lulu Delmay as Topsy," Windsor Theatre, Boston, Before 1856 (Folder 10.7)
    - "Wilson & Rankin's Mammoth Minstrels! Stetson's Double Uncle Tom's Cabin Co.," Wheeler Opera House, 1880s (Folder 10.7)
  - Stamps
    - Harriet Beecher Stowe, 2007 (Folder 1.53)
  - Ticket stub
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, Mammoth New England Company, undated (Folder 1.54)
  - Trade Cards
    - "A. R. Stover's Mammoth Spectacular Uncle Tom's Cabin," Opera House, Newport, undated (Folder 1.55)
    - C. H. Smith's Boston Uncle Tom's Cabin Company, circa 1870; [7 cards] (Folder 1.56)
    - C. H. Smith's Double Mammoth Uncle Tom's Cabin, circa 1880; [2 cards] (Folder 1.57)
    - "La Capanna Dello Zio Tom," Vero Estratto Di Carne Liebig, undated; [6 cards] (Folder 1.58)
    - Davis & Busby's Monster Uncle Tom's Cabin, undated (Folder 1.59)
    - Dime Eden Musee, 1889 (Folder 1.60)
    - Fred R. Wren's Mammoth Uncle Tom's Cabin Combination, undated (Folder 1.61)
    - George E. Steven's Original Uncle Tom's Cabin Combination, undated (Folder 1.62)
    - "Gögginger Nähgarne," Neuruppin, Germany: Oehmigke & Riemschneider, circa 1898 (Folder 1.63)
    - "Grand Jubilee Festival and Uncle Tom's Cabin," Wilgus Opera House, undated (Folder 1.64)
    - "The Ideal Company, Uncle Tom's Cabin," Elliot Hall, Newton, circa 1880s (Folder 1.65)
    - "Jay Rial's Ideal Uncle Tom's Cabin,", circa 1880s (Folder 1.66)
    - "Old Stowe House…," Andover, MA: Merrimack Mutual Insurance Co., circa 1890s (Folder 1.67)
    - "Onkel Toms Hutte, series 2," Holstein: Wagner & Co., 1929; [6 cards] (Folder 1.68)